

AVID SCHREIBER

dpschreiber@msn.com | 310-717-9799 | Culver City , CA 90230

Summary

Creative and analytical educational leader seeks new challenge. Long track record of success in creative and educational fields. Broad range of experience leading and managing teams. Easy-going but hard-working professional who possesses an innate desire to figure out how things work with an eye toward improving them. I feel a thrill of pride in finding solutions to seemingly intractable problems.

Skills

- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills Excellent at budgeting and financial analysis
- Proficient with Microsoft Office, Google Docs, Adobe Creative Suite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress
- Accomplished administrator with facility for multitasking
- · Creative and analytical thinker
- · Track record of effective collaboration

Work Experience

Producer - Documentary

12/2018 - Current

Zoochosis LLC | Los Angeles, CA

- Office manager during production of Hey PScott!, an animated episodic documentary
- Managed scheduling and budgeting

Campus Director / Dean of Academic Affairs

01/2016 - 03/2019

The Art Institute of California - Hollywood | North Hollywood, CA

- Executive responsible for all functional areas of college campus
- Managed P&L performance and fiscal planning
- On-boarded and developed relevant personnel
- Created and managed institution effective reports, generated SWOT analyses and action plans to address deficiencies
- Successfully led key projects which resulted in improved retention
- Established affiliation and articulation agreements with industry
- Successfully managed the WASC accreditation and reaffirmation process

Academic Director - Media Arts

07/2007 - 12/2015

The Art Institute of California - Los Angeles | Santa Monica, CA

- · Developed, administered and refreshed educational programs serving more than 2400 students
- · Established and updated schedule of classes and activities for school year
- · Evaluated effectiveness of training by surveying trainees and managers and collecting before- and after-data showing training impact
- Trained faculty procedures to facilitate consistent delivery of programmatic outcomes
- · Led community outreach to provide video and animation production services to local community

Associate Producer - Feature Film

08/2013 - 03/2014

40 Acres and a Mule, Filmworks | Brooklyn, NY

- Scheduled, budgeted script for Spike Lee's feature film Da Sweet Blood of Jesus
- · Managed liability and property insurance issues

Supervising Producer

01/2006 - 09/2008

94.7 The WAVE Radio Station | Los Angeles, CA Produced "Behind the Music" videos of jazz artists

- · Oversaw production schedules and logistics
- · Coordinated work of lighting and sound crews to streamline production operations on tight schedule

College Instructor - Video Production

07/2003 - 06/2007

The Art Institute of California - Los Angeles | Santa Monica, CA Taught courses in:

- Cinema Studies, Development, Directing, Editing, Lighting, Production Management, Screenwriting
- · Participated in continuing development and training to bolster professional teaching skills
- Built strong student rapport by driving classroom and online discussions and providing academic advising

Academic Coordinator - General Education

01/2001 - 5/2003

The Art Institute Online | Los Angeles, CA Supervised online general education classes

Freelance Camera and Lighting Crew

05/1996 - 03/2004

Multiple

Worked in Camera and Lighting departments on independent films:

Raising Genius, Phone Booth, 100 Deeds for Eddie McDowd, Face Value, Across the Line, The Corporate Ladder, Perfect Mate, Amityville Dollhouse-- and others

Freelance Segment Writer-Producer-Director

01/1991 - 01/2004

08/1988 - 02/1997

Multiple | Los Angeles, CA

Double Dare (Emmy winning kids' show), Celebrity Rehab with Dr. Drew, How's That Made?, The Dream Team, Debt, In the Dark, Unbelievable, Ultimate Revenge, Home and Family, The Match Game, Family Feud – among others...

College Instructor 09/1999 - 05/2000

The University of Miami | Coral Gables, FL

· Taught classes in cinema studies, screenwriting, producing

Sat on sabbatical and curriculum committees

College Instructor - Film/TV 01/1999 - 06/1999

New York University | New York, NY

Taught three courses in the undergraduate Film/TV program

Director of Creative Affairs (Story Department) 02/1998 - 11/1998

CLEAR Productions – Carl Reiner, president | Los Angeles, CA Acquired and developed narrative material for future film production

Story Analyst 03/1997 - 12/1997

Sanford-Pillsbury Productions | Santa Monica, CA

Read submissions for potential television or film production

Executive in Charge of Development

Brooksfilms Ltd - Mel Brooks, president| Los Angeles, CA

- Developed stories for feature film and television production
- Provided story notes to writers

Education and Training

Technical Degree: Frontend Web Development

Treehouse.com (in progress)

Master of Fine Arts: Film/TV New York University | New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts: Philosophy

University of California - Los Angeles | Los Angeles, CA Graduated Summa cum Laude and Phi Beta Kappa

Volunteer Work

Produced PSAs and provided video and animation production services for Heal the Bay, Hollywood CPR, The Sea Shepherd Society, Special Olympics, Surfrider Foundation, Train4Autism, The Trevor Project, UCLA Design for Sharing--and others

Websites,
Portfolios, Profiles

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-schreiber-b232486/
- https://www.DecisionsDecisions.world